Hello, all my friends, and welcome to exercise number 31.
So we are asked to write a program to remove an element from our post, the video and think about it.
So we have mentioned this idea in the course, in the lectures as previous.
So I need it from you to write them down.
This exercise is because these are very important and these are being asked in all interviews and being
asked in university.
So to do that, to solve this program, to remove an element from Iraq.
We should start by making the array that we need to remove at my ADDRE to remove the elements from math.
Like.
This is the IRA and IRA, and I will start by printing it before the.
Before that, even offering any end game.
So I will start the original
original.
And they I will I will use that as Ray the Orphan.
Class this thing and pass by Iraq, OK, this is the original that.
Or forage, you know, Saturday.
No.
Any moving element from how to do that, I will create and remove index.
I need to remove like 14.
This is the element that I need to remove this on.
Zero, one, two, three and four.
It is at index four.
OK.
So as I told you in the lectures in the previous videos and we see the animation that we need to shift
the elements back.
So I need to detect the element at first and then I need to remove it and shift that the elements after
to the left how to do so by using the four.
So I will create for loop and I quote to remove index.
We start from removing them.
They're removing Index I less than my air raid length minus one and I + +.
OK, so we start.
I told you that I need to remove 14 restart from this index, we remove it and I need to shift all the
elements to their left.
How to shift them and how this is done is by assigning them my array at index, I equal to my array
and index.
I am class one.
OK.
This is the trick we are not actually removing.
We are just replacing.
I am replacing four five six by by 14 and removing.
OK.
I am just shifting.
So removing, if you remember from their deck chairs before removing from every means, like updating
the following items and elements and like switching them, like shifting them.
OK, we are not actually removing.
I am replacing 14 by that, by its following element.
It's four, five six OK and four five six.
I am replacing it by its following, so it's following is not available.
So it is four five six.
OK.
This is why we used my array that length minus one.
And this is very important.
OK, now.
So since we cannot alter the size of an array after it's removing the last and the second last element
in the array will exist it twice.
OK, so array after removing.
System that's out there.
Brent.
Our original and this is the new array, after removing, I'm using Addres Dot to a string and my array.
Let's run and see.
And here we go.
We have two four two three five.
The first, the second, the third, the fourth element are the same.
14 have been removed and replaced by four or five six.
And since it is fixed size of six elements and we cannot modify that at that length of the array dynamically,
so it should duplicate that element.
OK.
So this is the trick behind removing the element from the array, and it's very common exercise exercise
and the questions that may ask in the interview.